Buck's Stove and Range Company vs. American Federation of Labor Court Records 5360
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Buck's Stove and Range Company vs. American Federation of Labor Court Records
1908-1919
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Buck's Stove and Range Company
5360
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Briefs, transcripts.
The collection contains legal documents pertaining to the case of Buck's Stove and Range Company vs. the American Federation of Labor, et al., 1907-1913, and a number of documents by the American Anti-Boycott Association.
2295986
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 22, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
In a six-year legal battle ending in the U.S. Supreme Court, the Buck's Stove and Range Company sought, and ultimatly failed, to have an American Federation of Labor boycott declared illegal on the grounds of anti-trust law.
As a result of a strike against the Buck's Stove and Range Company in St. Louis, Mo., the American Federation of Labor (A.F. of L.) placed the company on the list of firms not solicited by organized labor in its official paper, THE AMERICAN FEDERATIONIST, in May 1907. The company responded by filing suit against the A.F. of L., alleging that the boycott was in violation of anti-trust laws, and, in December 1907, obtained an injunction against the boycott. When the leadership of the A.F. of L. refused to comply with the injunction, leaders Samuel Gompers (president), Frank Morrison (secretary), and John Mitchell (vice-president) were found in contempt of court and sentenced to jail terms. After drawn out legal proceedings, the Supreme Court overruled the contempt charge on a technicality (1913).
Scope and Contents
Legal documents filed before the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia include: application fo a temporary restraining order against the defendants (Samuel Gompers, Frank Morrison, and John Mitchell); petition to have defendents ruled in contempt; copies of affidavits filed in court by plaintiff for use in hearing of application for temporary injunction against defendants (1907-1908).
Legal documents filed before the Court of Appeals, Destrict of Columbia include an appeal from the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia; brief and supplemental brief for appellee (Buck's Stove and Range Company); transcript of record of appeal from the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, Gompers et al., appellants (1908).
Finally, legal documents filed before the Supreme Court of the United States, including numerous briefs and supplemental briefs filed in behalf of Buck's Stove and Range Company (1910-1913).
Also includes publications by the American Anti-Boycott Association relating to the case, including arguments in support of a guilty ruling in the contempt case against Gompers, Morrison, and Mitchell; arguments in the contempt proceedings in the Court of Appeals of the District of Columbia; and transcript of the decision finding Gompers, Morrison, and Mitchell guilty of contempt (n.d.).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Antitrust law -- United States; Boycott -- United States; Labor laws and legislation--United States.; Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924.; Mitchell, John, 1870-1919.; Morrison, Frank, 1859-1949.; American Anti-Boycott Association.; Bucks Stove and Range Company.; American Federation of Labor
2295986
- Decision of Justice Wright in contempt proceedings against Samuel Gompers, Frank Morrison and John Mitchell, adjudging them guilty of contempt of court and imposing sentence thereof; together with newspaper editorial expression of the country thereon, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Published by American Anti-Boycott Association
- Brief for Appellee, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brief for respondent, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Motion of consolidate and advance, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Brief for the Buck's Stove and Range Company, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arguments in contempt proceeding, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Published by the American Anti-Boycott Association
- Copies of Affidavits filed in court by plaintiffs for use on hearing of application for a temporary injunction, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Application for a temporary injunction (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brief for the appellee, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Supplemental brief for the appellee, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Supplemental and reply brief for appellant in No. 190, respondent in no. 372, and appellee in no. 394, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Transcript of record, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Petition to have Samuel Gompers, Frank Morrison and John Mitchell, defendants, adjudged guilty of contempt, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Arguments of Daniel Davenport, Esq., General Counsel of the American Anti-Boycott Association in support of the decision of Judge Wright adjudging Samuel Gompers et al. guilty of contempt of court, and sentencing them to jail, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Arguments in support of petition to have Samuel Gompers, Frank Morrison and John Mitchell, defendants, adjudged guilty of contempt, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Appeal from the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Brief by committee, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Supplemental and reply brief for appellant in no. 190, respondent in no. 372, and appellee in no. 394, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)